SHREY GUPTA

Upcoming computer engineer and data science enthusiast possessing strong teamwork and organizational skills through hands-on experience working in various team projects. I am a person who is keen to find the logic behind everything and my whimsical jokes keep the environment lively.



🔀 shrey.gupta1904@gmail.com 📞 9717799361 💡 17, West Avenue Road, Punjabi Bagh, N. Delhi 🌐 www.shreygupta.net



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech), Computer Science & Engineering

Maharaja Agrasen Institute of Technology, New Delhi

August 2015 - Present CGPA: 8.66/10

CBSE | XII (Senior Secondary), Science

Springdales School, Pusa Road, New Delhi

May 2015

Aggregate: 90.8%

CBSE | X (Secondary)

Springdales School, Pusa Road, New Delhi

May 2013 CGPA: 10.00/10

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Intern | National Informatics Centre

01/07/2018 - 05/08/2018

Tasks/Achievements:

A research in the Machine Learning domain where we studied the various algorithms used in preprocessing of data, attribute selection and classification of different datasets.

Trainee | APTRON Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

01/06/2017 - 15/07/2017

Tasks/Achievements:

Developed a Hospital Management System, which further converged to an exclusive Doctor-Patient Management Application making it as user-friendly as possible.

Event Organizer | Techsurge (MAIT's Technical Fest)

06/04/2017 - 08/04/2017

Tasks/Achievements:

Being in the Core Team of the Annual Technical and Cultural Fest, I assisted the student body in organizing and managing different events.

TRAININGS

Machine Learning Foundation Nanodegree | Udacity (co-created by Kaggle)

January 2018 - April 2018

Tasks/Achievements:

An overview of descriptive & inferential statistics, data preprocessing & classification models and the various tools used (Anaconda, Scikit-Learn & TensorFlow).

The Web Developer Bootcamp and Amazon Web Services (AWS) | Udemy

August 2017 – December 2017

Tasks/Achievements:

- The course helped me gain knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON scripts and various frameworks such as MongoDB, NodeJS & BootStrap that are used in Front and Back end web development.
- Hands-on experience with Amazon Web Services(AWS) like S3, EC2, IAM and Lambda.

Android Basics Nanodegree by Google | Udacity (co-created by Google)

July 2017 – September 2017

Tasks/Achievements:

• A course provided by Google which helped me to brush up my Android Skills and I developed various apps with practical use-case scenarios (Quiz App, Tour Guide App, Inventory App etc.).

Android Application Development | APTRON Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

June 2017 - July 2017

Tasks/Achievements:

• An introductory Android course which helped me understand the basics and the working of the operating system itself and the development tools - XML, Java & Android Studio.

Python for Everybody Specialization | Coursera (by University of Michigan)

June 2016 - March 2017

Tasks/Achievements:

 This five-course specialization got me through Python 3 covering data structures, flow of control, accessing web data etc.

COMPETENCIES

- Leadership & teamwork
- Communicative
- Innovative & critical thinker

LANGUAGES

- Python
- C / C++
- HTML / CSS
- MongoDB / SQL

TOOLS

- Anaconda
- Amazon Web Services
- Android Studio
- loT / Raspberry Pi

PROJECTS

ZS Campus Beats Case Study | Team 3Musketeers

Tasks/Achievements:

• An immersive Case Study of a company, where we had to analyse the previous statistics and come up with a lucrative and efficient business plan for the new expansions planned by the company.

Face Recognition Using Hashing

Tasks/Achievements:

• We are working to create an efficient face recognition system that uses image hashing to recognize a face, this way the images don't get stored on the database and the privacy of a person is protected.

Unmanned Ground Vehicle for Mobility in Snowy Areas | DRUSE 2018 (DRDO)

Tasks/Achievements:

• We designed self-sufficient vehicle such that it can range over grounds with difficult terrains (those affected by avalanche and covered with loose snow).

DoctorOnTheGo | Android Application

Tasks/Achievements:

• A Doctor-Patient Appointment Management Application, helping doctors to manage patients' appointments, medications & prescriptions, according to the timeline of the treatment.

Model a Terrain | E - Yantra 2016

Tasks/Achievements:

- Qualified until the last stage in e Yantra Robotics Competition (eYRC 2016).
- Programmed the robot (Fire Bird V ATMEGA2560 Robotic Research Platform) to traverse an unknown terrain and build a 3D map of the same (using physics engine Blender) autonomously.

Home Automation | Internet of Things (IoT)

Tasks/Achievements:

• A Home Automation system by which different Home Appliances or Electronic/Electrical devices can be controlled using a web interface or an Android App.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Principle's Special Award | November 2014

Got the Principle's Special Award for outstanding contribution in Computers in various events.

School Prefect - Springdales School | Batch 2014 - 2015

Represented the student body and the school in various interschool events.